You'll believe a man can fly.
Superman is a science fiction, action, adventure
film directed by Richard Donner.
Mild-mannered Clark Kent works as a reporter at the Daily
Planet alongside his crush, Lois Lane.
Clark must summon his superhero alter-ego when the nefarious Lex
Luthor launches a plan to take over the world.
Clark Kent / Superman, played by Christopher Reeve.
Lois Lane, played by Margot Kidder.
Lex Luthor, played by Gene Hackman.
Jor-El, played by Marlon Brando.
Otis, played by Ned Beatty.
Perry White, played by Jackie Cooper.
Superman (also marketed as Superman: The Movie) is a 1978 superhero film based on
the DC Comics character Superman, portrayed by Christopher Reeve.
It is the first of four installments in the Superman
film series starring Reeve as Superman.
The film was directed by Richard Donner and written by Mario Puzo,
David Newman, Leslie Newman, and Robert Benton.
The film features an ensemble cast including Marlon Brando, Gene Hackman, Ned Beatty, Jackie Cooper, Glenn Ford, Trevor
Howard, Margot Kidder, Valerie Perrine, Maria Schell,  Terence Stamp, Phyllis Thaxter and Susannah York.
It depicts the origin of Superman, including his infancy as Kal-El of Krypton, son of
Jor-El (Brando), and his youthful years in the rural town of Smallville.
Disguised as reporter Clark Kent, he adopts a mild-mannered disposition in Metropolis and develops a
romance with Lois Lane (Kidder) while battling the villainous Lex Luthor (Hackman).
Ilya Salkind had the idea of a Superman film in 1973 and, after a difficult process with DC
Comics, the Salkinds bought the rights to the character the following year.
Several directors, most notably Guy Hamilton, and screenwriters were
associated with the project before Donner was hired to direct.
Tom Mankiewicz was drafted in to rewrite the script and
was given a creative consultant credit.
It was decided to film both Superman and its sequel Superman II (1980) simultaneously, with
principal photography beginning in March 1977 and ending in October 1978.
Tensions arose between Donner and the producers, and a decision was made to stop filming the
sequel, of which 75 percent had already been completed, and finish the first film.
The most expensive film made up to that point, with a budget of $55 million, Superman premiered at The Kennedy Center in Washington, DC,
on December 10, 1978, and was released in the United Kingdom on December 14, and in the United States on December 15.
The film was a critical and financial success; its worldwide box office earnings of
$300 million made it the second-highest-grossing release of the year.
It received praise for Reeve's performance and John Williams's musical score.
The film was nominated for Best Film Editing, Best Music (Original Score) and Best Sound at the 51st
Academy Awards and received a Special Achievement Academy Award for Visual Effects.
Groundbreaking in its use of special effects and science fiction/fantasy storytelling, the film's
legacy presaged the mainstream popularity of Hollywood's superhero film franchises.
In 2017, Superman was selected for preservation by the
Library of Congress's National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of galaxy, journalist, saving
the world, secret identity, crime fighter.
The tone is thought_provoking.